Abraham: What is open source information?
Open-source information is
information that is publicly
available, and anyone can obtain by
request, purchase or observation.
Information to be considered open source
can be published or broadcast for a
public audience, available to the public
by request, subscription or purchase.
It can also be seen or heard
casually or made available at a
public meeting or by visiting a
place or event open to the public.
Open-source intelligence involves data
and information that is available to
the general public and can be used
by security specialists and threat
actors alike to focus their efforts
on specific areas of interest.
Nicole: Cyber criminals can use
open-source intelligence to identify
weaknesses to exploit in networks such
as accidental leaks of information
through social media, open ports or
unsecured internet connected devices.
Cyber criminals can also access
publicly available information
through social media sites.
Just think about all that information
people put online, ages, addresses, email
addresses, family and pet names, what
they’re doing, where they’re going, what
they believe in, what they have bought.
The list is endless and gives plenty
of information to cyber criminals.
That's just a small portion of
the information that’s available.
Abraham: Think about all the
other information that can
be obtained via the internet.
Cyber criminals will build an image
of who they are pretending to be,
so they can talk confidently about
it and make you feel for them to
increase your sense of familiarity.
They make you more likely to do what
they want, such as click a link.
This is called pretexting.
They may, for example, research Instagram
and see that you have a pet dog and when
they make contact, could talk about how
they’ve been working at the dog shelter.
This will build an emotional
connection and establish themselves
as a good and trustworthy person.
Nicole: So, what useful information can
be gained through social engineering?
Cybercriminals through social
engineering use multiple tactics to
gain information such as passwords,
usernames and banking details.
They create websites which look
legitimate using trademarks and logos.
They rely on an individual’s
trust that it must be 'legit'.
By accessing one person’s email
password they also have access to
all their contacts and many people
use the same password so they may
have access to their social media
and all their social media contacts.
Think of all those emails about winning
money or prizes, be eligible for a tax
refund, helping someone out abroad by
accepting their money into your account.
They are all ways social
engineering takes place so just
think have you ever been a victim.